konstella.com 2017-04-19

# Privacy

Welcome to [Konstella](https://www.konstella.com/). We understand that privacy and security are super important to you, your children and your schools. Please read our policy and contact us if you have any questions or concerns. The effective date of this policy is Mar 8th, 2016.

#### Information You Provide to Us

_Verification Process._ You can join your school by: (1) having a verified user at your school invite you, (2) providing us your email, your children's names, classrooms and schools, so that we can forward it to your school gatekeepers (verified users who volunteer to verify other users at your schools) (3) other methods we may develop over time. If you do not confirm your email address, we may choose to restrict or terminate your account. We may choose to retain all verification-related information indefinitely to assist with future verifications, even if you do not complete the verification. If you decide not to verify the account and would like us to delete your non-public verification information, please contact us. 

If you request to create an account on Konstella, we retain your request information indefinitely and use it to provide the requested notification and assist with your verification. If you change your mind about wanting to be notified, please contact us. 

_Profile Information._ We allow you to create a personal profile and submit information such as your phone number, your children's names, genders, schools, and etc. As the default setting, your information is visible by other verified users at your schools. We may give you ways to hide some of this profile information, but your name and school is always visible to verified users at your school. Your children's names (if provided) are always visible to verified users at your school. 

_Communications with Other Members._ We give you a variety of ways to communicate and share content with other parents at your schools and districts. If you choose, some of these communications are visible to the entire school and other schools in the district. Other communications (such as messages between you and another individual member) may be visible only to a subset of your school members. In some cases, we may limit your ability to edit or remove content from Konstella. 

_Third Party Offers._ We know that you do not want marketing from third parties, so we will never turn over your personally identifiable information to third party marketers without consent. 

In the future, we may create a section of the site to present offers for goods and services (upon approval by your school/district). If you decide to participate with an offer, you may be presented with an opportunity to share information with the merchant. If you accept the offer, then we'll send the information you requested to share with the merchant. We won't transmit information to the merchant until you explicitly ask us to do so. At that point, the data we deliver to the merchant will be governed by the merchant's privacy policy, not ours. 

_Data Modification/Deletion._ You can delete your account by contacting us. Alternatively, you can delete most types of individual content items. Deleting your account will delete all content you provided, except that we may choose to retain content incorporated into conversations (and, as applicable, parent discussions); and we may attribute that content to your name even after you depart. If you are the subject of an unauthorized profile, please contact us. 

#### Information We Collect Automatically

_Server Logs._ Like most websites, we automatically collect information about your visits to our website and your interaction with our email, including the browser you are using, the URLs you came from and go to, your computer's operating system, your IP address, and usage and browsing habits. We use this information to diagnose and resolve server problems, analyze trends, track user movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information. 

_Cookies._ Like most websites, our website uses "cookies," small data files stored on your computer which include a unique identifier. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You can configure your browser to reject cookies, but doing so will prevent you from logging into our website. 

_Web Beacons._ Our website and emails may contain "web beacons" that help us measure and track member activity. Some of these web beacons come from us; others come from our service providers. We currently use Google Analytics as our service provider. 

**Information We Get About You From Third Parties.** To start the school, we may obtain information about your children's names, their classrooms and schools from your teachers and parent organizations. Parents and teachers at your schools may provide us with, and share with other parents, information about you (even if you are not a member), such as your name, email address, typically found in school directories. If you aren't a member but would like us to delete non-public information about you, please contact us. 

**Respecting Other Parents' Privacy.** One of Konstella's central tenets is that parents should be able to communicate only amongst themselves. For this reason, we restrict who can access your school website and take efforts to exclude others from the conversation. For example, we don't let public web search engines (such as Google) index member-submitted content. 

Given this norm, taking information shared by one parent to another and sharing it outside the school/district violates other users' expectations and is a serious breach of trust. Therefore, you may not share other parents' information or any communications sent through Konstella with anyone outside the school(s)/district(s) to which the post was distributed without the author's permission. Also, you may not gather information from the website, either manually or on an automated basis (such as through scripts, robots, crawlers or spiders). Without limiting the foregoing, it is not OK to provide other parent's information from the website to third party marketers. 

Violating this provision may lead to a loss of account privileges, potentially including a permanent ban from the website. 

**Email Subscriptions.** We will alert you of various activities within your school or district via email. You can manage your email preferences on your account settings page. 

**Contractors/Service Providers.** Third party contractors may have access to our databases. These contractors sign a standard confidentiality agreement. 

Some of our site's functionality (e.g. the feedback button) may be operated by third party service providers, and in the course of providing this functionality, these service providers may obtain some of your personal data from you directly or transferred from us to facilitate your usage of this service. 

**Government Relations and Lawsuits.** We may disclose data about you to the government if we are required to do so or as we think is prudent for safety or security reasons; and you authorize us to make these disclosures. We may also disclose data about you in connection with actual or potential legal proceedings (a) in response to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants or orders, (b) if we are required to do so in other ways, (c) if such disclosures might mitigate our liability, or (d) to enforce our rights. 

**Limits on Our Abilities.** While we work hard to respect your privacy, like any other complex web service, we might inadvertently use or disclose your data in ways inconsistent with this statement. For example, a temporary software glitch could lead to public display of your personal data despite your contrary preferences. We might also make ad hoc uses of your data in ways not mentioned here. In these anomalous situations, we will try to rectify the anomaly as soon as we can. 

**Data Retention.** Subject to any mandatory obligations to delete data, we may choose to retain information in our server logs, our databases and our records indefinitely. 

**Security.** To enhance the security of your interactions with the site, Konstella uses https on its web pages to prevent unauthorized interception of your communications during your site visits and takes measures to protect passwords from unauthorized access. We also use a variety of security measures to protect your information in our databases. However, please be aware that perfect security does not exist on the Internet. 

**Amendment.** This privacy policy can be modified in accordance with the amendment procedures described in that document. 

**Contact Us.**
